Supida Leelamaneepong

สุภิดา ลีลามณีพงศ์

513-515 Mahachai Road, Pranakorn, Bangkok, 10200, Thailand Telephone: 081 617-0404, Email: supida.leelamaneepong@gmail.com

CAREER SUMMARY

A project manager with over 10 years of software project management experience ranging from Program level management to detail software project. Coaching and mentoring junior project managers and built their skills to meet the highest standard. Recognized for providing software project process improvement as well as refined project delivery framework. Proven management skill in analysing, decision making, trouble-shooting and driving for a successful completion of the projects.

CAREER HISTORY

Deutsche Bank

Regulatory Reporting Team Supporting Officer (1 year contract; Sep 2014 – Aug 2015)

- Managed a transition project to migrate Bank's Regulatory Reports to a new report automation system.
- Be the center point of contact between business users and the technical project team; BA, development, project management as well as support team.
- Requirement management; gathering and analysing user requirements on the reports as well as finalized business requirement documents for the technical team.
- Drive and negotiate the scope of project delivery to ensure the reports are fit for use for submission to regulators.
- Perform UAT on reports delivered and prepare end users' acception before report go-live.
- Act as first level support to business users and trouble shoot issues on report prior to raising issues to Support team.

Software Park Thailand

Freelance IT Trainer - Software Team Leader Management Training Program

- Designed and developed course content in leadership skill for IT team leaders.
- Deliver classroom training and conducting the workshop and group discussion session.
- Mentoring individual student post classroom training on the application of knowledge obtained from the classroom into their work.
- Provide consultation to the students on their management related topics.

Thomson Reuters Software Thailand

Sep 2010 – Feb 2013 Senior Product Manager (Enterprise Platform)

- Led and managed the team of product managers in Bangkok in delivering products for the Enterprise Platform Domain.
- Provided guidance and support to Product managers to ensure the delivery of new software product.
- Represented the product management team in redefining method of work process with development team.

- Represented Product Management group in Asia on product enquiries and assisted the Business Development team in providing information on the new features of products within the Enterprise Platform domain.
- Assisted the Asia Product Manager in producing the client notification messages and announcement on new and updated product features.

May 2008 – Sep 2010 Senior Project Manager (Time Series for Common Platform)

- Reporting to Time Series Programme Manager and managed sub-programme and projects under Times Series
 for Common Platform Programme to deliver the Real-time time series and Historical data Infrastructure which
 feeds the various client applications.
- Managed between 4-7 end to end projects in parallel from Business Planning phase through to Deployment into various Reuters Technical Data Centres in both the US and Europe regions.
- Engaged with all relevant groups under Reuters Proposition Delivery framework and ensure that all Time Series stakeholders and owners are well aware of and understood the project scope to gain Technical and Business Commitment of the project.
- Collaborated with a large number of operation groups from Business Analyst, Architect, Developments both internal and external, Quality Assurance and Technical Operations to Content Operations in building up the project plan which includes working closely with the relevant resource managers in balancing the resources to minimize impact to the committed project as a result of Programme re-prioritization of projects.
- Managed projects which includes both 3rd party development as well as different groups within Thomson Reuters as team members.
- Co-ordinate the release of the Time Series API software to desktop application team so that the final solution is delivered in line with Thomson Reuters Eikon project Roadmap.
- Planned and managed the alignment of software releases from each individual projects within the Time Series for Common Platform Programme Roadmap from integration testing through to deployment in Pre-Production and Production environments in both US and UK locations.
- Managed risks and issues of projects as well as tracking the project and provide regular reports to the Programme management team.
- Managed changes to the project that have impacts on the overall delivery of the Programme and ensure that these changes are communicated and approved at the programme level.
- Managed and responsible for the performance of project managers within the Bangkok office under the Program in delivering the project work streams.
- Contribute to the setting up of the various software development and project delivery management processes adopted within Times Series team.

Jun 2004 – Apr 2008 Senior Project Manager (Enterprise Information System)

- Lead the team of 7 Project Mangers within the Bangkok office as part of the Global IMS Product and Project Management team.
- Represented the Bangkok Project Management group and lead the roll out of the new Global Proposition Delivery process within the Enterprise Information Management System.
- Coached and mentoring junior Project Managers to reach their full potential.
- Oversaw the integrity and quality of the production of monthly project status reports from each project managers under supervision.
- Consolidate and summarize the monthly project status reports from all projects within Bangkok which was the inputs for the Global Product and Project Highlights Report for Senior Management.
- Adopted and defined the Proposition Delivery model for medium to small size projects and rolled out the new process to the Enterprise Information domain prior to the model being defined by the Global Project Office Group.
- Plan and lead the execution of the roll out of the new Reuters EPM Project Management Tool within Enterprise Information Management System domain successfully according to plan.
- Represented the domain as Project Managers in the Software Engineering Process Group within the company to

- maintain consistency in the area of project management practice and knowledge across all domains.
- Managed new software development projects for the Osaka Stock Exchange from project initiation phase through to software rolled out at the Exchange.
- Managed 3rd party development projects which includes the management of collaboration between the outsourced teams as well as the internal Reuters teams.
- Managed Bloomberg B-Pipe Feed Handler project which involves the collaboration with the industry competitor.
- Produce the project plan which consolidates the plans from various Centre of Excellence involved in the project. Also owned the Proposition Delivery checklist and host all the review checkpoints in order to gain agreement and commitment from various delivering groups as well as stakeholders.
- Engage with the Reuters Technical Governance group to ensure the projects are aligned with the technical standards and arranged all the technical review meetings.
- Organize relevant training for support organization to ensure the readiness to support when the product is officially launched.

Jan 2002 – May 2004 Product Delivery Manager

- Managed software product delivery from requirement management through to software release.
- Delivered software development project using the Capability Maturity Model for Software Process Improvement (CMMI) and ensuring the fast delivery of software does not compromise the process.
- Managed stakeholders' requirement expectations by aligning understanding with the development team to ensure the on time delivery of software.
- Provided support and guidance to the development team in handling the large amount of requests received from product managers as well as provided negotiated priority list of the workload for the development team.
- Interfaced with senior managers to ensure the critical issues raised by customers receive the appropriate course of action within the appropriate time frame.
- Worked closely with the transition managers and transitioning development team prior to the end of product transition period to ensure the smooth "start of support" from Bangkok Development Centre.
- Maintained the integrity of the Reuters Software Thailand Product Portal by regularly updating the information on the website and Project Portal as well as providing the updated information to the Project Office Coordinator for Balanced Scorecard.
- Provided classroom training as part of the company induction program to all new joiners on the Reuters Products and Reuters Data.

Reuters Thailand Limited

Feb 2000 – Dec 2001 Product Marketing Executive

- Accomplished the project of making Thai language news available on Reuters Integrated Data Network, the
 Reuters real time distribution network. This includes creating business justification, defined news content, coproduced the product requirement specification document with Thai Data Source Owner for development team
 and ensures the end result is visible on desktop and web applications.
- Lead the launch of a Reuters premium Desktop product, 3000Xtra in Thailand. Prepared all necessary information in terms of front end applications to back end data delivery infrastructure, leased line information, pricing and also organized the product training for the sales and support team.
- Provided administration information for Subscriber Administrator for service permissioning and billing.
- Assisted with the launch event organized by Reuters introducing customers to the new premium product, Reuters 3000Xtra.
- Co-ordinate with the product managers in promoting the new web-based products, Reuters Investor Service and Reuters Market Monitor in Thailand.
- Responsible for marketing aspects of Reuters technology oriented products such as the Trading Room

- Architecture (TRIARCH) and Graphic application.
- Explored the possibility of providing Reuters 3000 over the internet connection (R3@I) to the clients in the remote area where leased line connection from Bangkok is not practical.

Mar 1997 – Jan 2000 Customer Relation Executive

- Managed customer accounts and ensured customers satisfaction and utilization of the products subscribed by paying regular visit to all clients.
- Provided product training to Reuters customers in all forms from classroom training to one-on-one training, covering from Desktop applications to Transaction applications.
- Provided first line support to Reuters customers on both the data information query as well as filtered technical query for the technical engineers while performing the help desk role.

EDUCATION

MSc. Computers in Industry (1994-1996)

Middlesex University, London, UK

BSc. Mathematics and Statistics (1991-1994)

Queen Mary and Westfield College, University of London, London, UK

CERTIFICATIONS AND COURSES

Professional Certification

Project Management Institute PMP Certificate (2006-2009)

Selected courses

- The Management Challenge for First Level Managers
- Managing Cross-Cultural Work Interfaces
- IT Risk Management, The George Washington University, School of Business and Public Management
- Project Leadership, Management and Communications, The George Washington University, School of Business and Public Management
- Leading and Coaching Project Teams

References

- Ms Prapharluck Pornbenjapukkul, Project Office Manager at Thomson Reuters Thailand
- Nancy Selph, Director Strategic Operations, GTO Strategy, Architecture and Innovation at Deutsche Bank New York.